

Dalila Ksir

O Home: Street 20 Mars - Remada, 3240, Remada, Tunisia

Email: <u>ksirdalila1991@gmail.com</u> **Phone:** (+216) 27689377

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ksir-dalila-870

Gender: Female Date of birth: 03/01/1991 Nationality: Tunisian

Professional with extensive years of experience in the field of local development, combined with training in project management and a strong ability to acquire new knowledge. Able to work both collaboratively and independently, I demonstrate a strong sense of organization and proven skills in coordination and leadership.

SKILLS

Project management / Activity monitoring and evaluation / Managementmethods Coordination/ strategy development/ inbound call reception / negotiation techniques /Needs evaluation/ Report writing/ Intervention planning/ Leadership/ Knowledge of data collection and monitoring methods and tools/ Proficiency in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Microsoft Teams, etc.).

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/01/2021 - 31/03/2023]

Local Coordinator for ODD16 Portfolio

UNDP

City: Remada Country: Tunisia

As Local Coordinator for ODD16 Portfolio at the municipality of Remada, my main

responsibilities are as follows:

The Hub (consolidation and duplication):

At this level, my main role is to support and accompany the Remada Hub (which includes 19 members from the municipality, administration, media, youth, and associations) to ensure the following tasks:

The legal establishment of the hub (a multi-stakeholder group of local interests) Implementation of the hub's communication strategy

Planning and implementation of the short-term budget and action plan (programmatic and logistical preparation of activities and meetings, coordination between portfolio colleagues and hub members)

Motivating hub members to conduct or participate in other activities outside of its action plan to ensure their sustainability.

Localization of ODD16:

This involves direct and indirect support for ODD16 portfolio projects:

Direct support: identification of stakeholders, logistical and technical support (organizing workshops), coordination, data collection (surveys, mapping, etc.), identifying equipment

needs, accompanying project teams in the field, and monitoring progress in the Remada vouth center.

Indirect support: sharing knowledge of the context and actors, contacting other actors operating in the Remada region and participating in events, reporting on activities, etc.

[01/11/2019 - 31/12/2020]

Field Coordinator for the PBF Project

UNDP

City: Remada Country: Tunisia

As a young UN volunteer, I held the position of local coordinator at the Municipality of Remada in the "Peace Building Fund" project, which was financed by three organizations: UNDP, UN Women, and UNESCO, working in collaboration to achieve the project's goal of integrating youth into local affairs. As part of this project, I was tasked with various responsibilities, including:

Internal coordination with the project team to organize work and exchange ideas and experiences, including report production, terrain diagnosis (mapping, surveys, etc.), reporting, information sharing, resources and face-to-face and virtual meetings, project planning, monitoring, and evaluation.

External coordination: This involves collaborating with all stakeholders involved, including local communities, administrations, media, young men and women, and associations, to establish effective external coordination. This coordination involves organizing, supervising, and motivating these stakeholders to develop a communication plan, action plan, as well as networking among them.

Supporting local communities to develop more accessible municipal structures for NEETs.

Analyzing training and material needs.

Providing technical expertise to young project initiators to assist them in implementing their 16 community initiatives and giving effective and constructive advice.

Motivating associations to mobilize young people and participate in various project calls.

Monitoring and evaluating different project stages.

[01/03/2015 - 31/12/2017]

Project Coordinator

Association for Youth and Development in Remada

City: Remada Country: Tunisia

As a volunteer coordinator for the project "Together to promote Remada" with the Remada Youth and Development Association, my main goal is to improve citizen participation and public relations management in the city by beautifying green spaces and ensuring their maintenance and modernization. To achieve this, I have several important responsibilities, including:

Coordinating between local authorities and the various civil society actors involved in the project.

Organizing and leading follow-up and progress meetings with participating teams. Defining, managing, and monitoring the schedule and allocation of tasks.

Ensuring the logistical and administrative organization of internal events such as meetings, webinars, and conference calls.

Working closely with citizens, NGOs, administrations, and the municipality to identify the needs of the region and respond effectively - Strengthening collaboration with local authorities to better promote our mission and develop partnerships with individuals and organizations sharing our values.

Organizing community events to foster engagement and participation, such as volunteer days, setup workshops, and cleaning campaigns.

Conducting awareness campaigns to inform citizens of the importance of preserving a clean environment and encouraging their voluntary participation.

Creating a park model to make our design more visible.

Providing support to citizens during the planting and preparation of a family park.

EDUCATION AND FORMATION

[01/10/2021 - 10/09/2022]

Training on international best practices in project management and local development planning.

A training divided into four sessions organized by the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)

[15/03/2018 - 15/06/2018] **Project Studies**

Conducted by the organization UNOPS in Tataouine

[01/09/2017 – 31/12/2017] **HP Life training**

Field: Business Plan Study, organized by UNIDO in Tataouine

[01/05/2017 - 05/05/2017] **Human Development**

INSTITUTION NAME: Hilfeswerk Organization, Tataouine

[01/01/2017 - 04/01/2017] **Communication**

INSTITUTION NAME: Hilfeswerk Organization, Tataouine

[01/06/2016 - 10/06/2016] **Computer Science: JavaScript field**

A training organized by the Al Inssar Training Center in partnership with the University of Cambridge

[15/10/2009 - 15/06/2014] Bachelor's degree in Italian language, civilizations, and literature

Field: International Business, University of Gabes

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Arabic

Other language(s):

French

LISTENING C2 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

English

LISTENING B1 READING C1 WRITING B1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

Italian

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

REFERENCES

Portfolio Coordination Project Supervisors for SDG16

Regional Coordinator: Abdelhafidh Chaibi Contact: abdelhafidh.chaibi@undp.org

Deputy Resident Representative • CO/VE UNDP: Eduardo.lopez-mancisidor Contact : eduardo.lopez-mancisidor@undp.org

Project PBF Supervisor

Project Manager and Gender and Inclusion Analyst • CO/TN Ghalia Kacem Contact : ghalia.kacem@undp.org

President of the Youth and Development Association in Remada

Project Manager: Radhia Dhieb Contact: Jeunes-ajd@hotmail.fr